https://www.sea.edu/about_sea/privacy_policy

Ready for an adventure with a purpose? Request info »
Our Ships
Why SEA Semester?
Shop the SEA Store
Contact Us
Request Info
Privacy Policy
This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for SEA Semester | Sea Education Association (identified as SEA throughout the rest of this privacy policy). This policy informs you of the information that we collect from you at this site, what we do with it, and to whom it may be disseminated. Based on this information, you can make an informed decision about whether and how to use this site.
Information Collection and Use
SEA is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. SEA collects information from our visitors at several different points on our Website.
Cookies
No personally identifiable information (e-mail address, name, etc.) is collected with the cookies that we set.
We use Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show you our ads on sites across the Internet. SEA and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone’s past visit to our website.
Different browsers have different cookie-settings. You can choose to allow Websites to create cookies for you in your "trusted sites" (like SEA), to warn you before you create them in your local Intranet zone, and to give you an option to never allow them in a "restricted zone." See the "Help" section of your particular browser for more information on working with cookies.
You may also be interested in Google Analytic’s currently available opt-outs for the web.
Web Statistics
We may use third-party analytics tools to collect information about use of this site. These tools collect information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from these tools only to improve this site.
In addition, we use a tool called Google Analytics to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and to gather broad demographic information, along with 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender, and interests) for aggregate use for reporting and donation purposes. The analytics tools we use collect only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. Although the analytics tools plant a persistent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser.
Sharing
We will share aggregated demographic information with our donors and Trustees & Overseers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We only share this information so that we can secure funding to continue operating.
Links
This Website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that SEA does not claim any responsibility for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Website. In particular, please note that SEA’s online application is hosted by a third-party provider, inResonance. When completing the online application, you are subject to the Terms and Conditions of the third-party provider, inResonance, including inResonance's site terms (Terms of Service, Privacy Policy, and Copyright Policy.)
Security
This Website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. SEA uses industry standard security measures to ensure that information provided by you, including your personally identifiable information, is not lost, misused, altered, or unintentionally destroyed. We also use software to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. This website is monitored to ensure its proper operation, to verify the functioning of applicable security features and for related purposes. Anyone using this website expressly consents to such monitoring. While we strive to ensure that information submitted through this site is protected, SEA cannot guarantee the security of any data submitted via its website.
Surveys and Feedback section
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via Web surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.
Request Information Forms
If a user elects to fill out one of our forms to request more information, we ask them to choose a topic/s that they would like more information about. SEA will send periodic updates regarding the topic/s. The user has the option to unsubscribe at any time. Any email messages, contact forms and other customizations that users create through this site will contain personally identifiable information including, but not limited to email addresses and any other information you choose to provide to help us answer your inquiry. The information that you voluntarily submit will also be disclosed to SEA employees or officials, or those under contract with SEA, who have a "need to know" your information for the purposes of fulfilling their job responsibilities and responding to your requests.
Notification of Changes
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this page.
Donor Privacy
Our donor privacy policy may be viewed by clicking here.
Questions or Comments
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Website, you can contact us at .(JavaScript must be enabled to view this email address)
Definitions
Cookies are files that a website can place on your computer. A cookie file contains unique information that the issuing website can use to store data such as your user name or email address track webpages you have visited, record the date when you last looked at a specific webpage, or to identify your session at a particular website, for example. A cookie file allows the website to recognize you as you click through pages on the site and when you later revisit the site. A website can use cookies to "remember" your preferences, and to record your browsing behavior on the Web. Although you can prevent websites from placing cookies on your computer by using your browser’s preference menu, disabling cookies may affect your ability to view or interact with some websites.
An “Internet Protocol Address” or “IP Address” is a series of numbers that identifies each computer and machine connected to the Internet. An IP address enables a server on a computer network to send you the file that you have requested on the Internet. The IP address disclosed to us generally identifies the computer or device from which you are accessing the Internet, or a server owned by your Internet Service Provider. Because it is machine-specific, rather than person-specific, an IP address is not, in and of itself, personally identifiable information.
“Personally Identifiable Information” is any information that could reasonably be used to identify you, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, Social Security number, birth date, bank account information, credit card information, or any additional information provided by you or any combination of information that could be used to identify you.
Apply Now
Student Login
Voyagers
Give Today
Alumni
Crew
SEA Currents Blog
Contact Us
Search
Undergraduate Study AbroadSemester ProgramsCaribbean Reef ExpeditionClimate & SocietyColonization to Conservation in the CaribbeanThe Global OceanMarine Biodiversity & ConservationOcean ExplorationOceans & ClimateSustainability in Polynesian Island Cultures & EcosystemsSummer ProgramsPacific Reef ExpeditionProtecting the Phoenix IslandsTermsSpring 2021Summer 2021Fall 2021Spring 2022Summer 2022DestinationsCaribbeanFiji/Samoan IslandsHawai'iNorth AtlanticNew ZealandPolynesiaPhoenix Islands Protected AreaProgram SearchGap YearAtlantic OdysseyOcean ExplorationPacific Odyssey (Spring 2021)Program SearchHigh SchoolSEA Expedition (At Sea)SEASCape (On Shore)SEA Quest (Online)Program SearchAdmissions & AidUndergraduate AdmissionsHow to ApplyA Day in the LifeSEA Semester Program CostsPlanning AheadAdvising HoursContact a Recent AlumFor Accepted StudentsFor ParentsUndergraduate Financial AidFinancial AidAffordabilityFederal Financial AidInstitutional AidMerit & Special ScholarshipsNeed-Based AidTestimonialsWhat's Included?Gap Year AdmissionsHow to ApplyGap Year Program CostsGap Year Financial AidFinancial AidHigh School AdmissionsHow to ApplyHigh School Program CostsFor ParentsHigh School Financial AidFinancial AidAdmissions StaffAcademicsSEA Semester AcademicsCourses, Credits & SyllabiAffiliated & Sending InstitutionsAcademic ScheduleSEA Semester FacultyFacultyResearch at SEACollaborationsFunded ProjectsPapers and PublicationsSEA Data AccessCollaborative ProgramsFor Faculty & AdvisorsInformation for Faculty & AdvisorsWhy SEA Semester?Educational PhilosophyAcademic CreditAffiliated InstitutionsHealth & SafetyAffordabilityK-12 Lesson PlansAboutWho We AreMission & VisionHistoryRecent Awards & RecognitionDiversityTrustees & OverseersSenior ManagementFinancial InformationPress KitLogos & UsageVisiting SEADiscover Woods HoleWhy SEA Semester?Health & Safety at SEAAlumni StoriesTestimonialsWhy Study the OceanAbout SEA ShipsSSV Corwith CramerSSV Robert C. SeamansShips' History360° Ship TourShipboard EquipmentShip ScheduleCurrent Robert C. Seamans VoyageCurrent Corwith Cramer VoyagePast VoyagesDigital PublicationsEmploymentFollow Us on Social MediaSupport UsWays to GiveAnnual FundPlanned GivingGive OnlineVolunteeringDonor Privacy Policy
